Desperate times. Desperate measures.
Mission: Impossible - Rogue Nation is a action, adventure
film directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
Ethan and team take on their most impossible mission yet—eradicating 'The Syndicate', an
International and highly-skilled rogue organization committed to destroying the IMF.
Ethan Hunt, played by Tom Cruise.
William Brandt, played by Jeremy Renner.
Benji Dunn, played by Simon Pegg.
Ilsa Faust, played by Rebecca Ferguson.
Luther Stickell, played by Ving Rhames.
Lane, played by Sean Harris.
Mission: Impossible – Rogue Nation is a 2015 American action spy
film written and directed by Christopher McQuarrie.
It is the sequel to Mission: Impossible – Ghost Protocol (2011) and the
fifth installment in the Mission: Impossible film series.
The film stars Tom Cruise, Jeremy Renner, Simon Pegg, Ving Rhames,
Rebecca Ferguson, Sean Harris, Sagar Radia and Alec Baldwin.
In the film, Impossible Missions Force agent Ethan Hunt (Cruise) and his IMF team, who, subsequent to their disbandment and Hunt's
pursuit by the Central Intelligence Agency, must fight The Syndicate, an international group of rogue government agents.
McQuarrie, who completed uncredited rewrites for Mission: Impossible – Ghost Protocol, was
announced as the director of Mission: Impossible – Rogue Nation in August 2013.
The returns of Cruise, Renner, Pegg and Rhames were confirmed by July 2014 while the screenplay was also developed by
Pearce and Will Staples; it was ultimately solely credited to McQuarrie, with Pearce receiving story credit.
Ferguson, Harris and Baldwin rounded out the cast that October.
Principal photography was from August 2014 to March 2015, in key locations including
London, Vienna, Casablanca, and at Leavesden Studios in Hertfordshire, UK.
The film's official title was revealed in March 2015.
Mission: Impossible – Rogue Nation premiered at the Vienna State Opera (one of its filming locations) on July
23, 2015, and was theatrically released in the United States by Paramount Pictures a week later.
The film received critical acclaim for McQuarrie's direction, screenplay, action
sequences, and the performances of Cruise, Pegg, and Ferguson.
It grossed $710.9 million worldwide, becoming the eighth-highest-grossing film of
2015 and the then-second-highest-grossing film in the franchise.
A sequel, Mission: Impossible – Fallout, was released in 2018.
The film explores themes of mask, mission, assassin, london, england, spy.